{
    "lesson_10": [
      { "back": "あります", "front": "to exist (inanimate objects)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "います", "front": "to exist (animate objects)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "いろいろ", "front": "various", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おとこのひと", "front": "man", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おんなのひと", "front": "woman", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おとこのこ", "front": "boy", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おんなのこ", "front": "girl", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "いぬ", "front": "dog", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ねこ", "front": "cat", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ぞう", "front": "elephant", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "き", "front": "tree", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "まど", "front": "window", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "でんち", "front": "battery", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "はこ", "front": "box", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "スイッチ", "front": "switch", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "れいぞうこ", "front": "refrigerator", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "テーブル", "front": "table", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ベッド", "front": "bed", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "たな", "front": "shelf", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ドア", "front": "door", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ポスト", "front": "postbox, mailbox", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ビル", "front": "building", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ATM", "front": "ATM", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "コンビニ", "front": "convenience store", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "こうえん", "front": "park", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "きっさてん", "front": "café, coffee shop", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "や", "front": "store (e.g., bookshop, flower shop)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "のりば", "front": "bus stop, taxi stand", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "けん", "front": "prefecture", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "うえ", "front": "above, on top", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "まえ", "front": "in front of, before", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "うしろ", "front": "behind", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "みぎ", "front": "right", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ひだり", "front": "left", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "そと", "front": "outside", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "なか", "front": "inside", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "となり", "front": "next to", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "あいだ", "front": "between", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ちかく", "front": "near, nearby", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "した", "front": "under, below, beneath", "status": "notRemember" }
    ],
    "lesson_9": [
      { "back": "すき", "front": "like", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ハンサム", "front": "handsome", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "きらい", "front": "dislike", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "わかります", "front": "understand", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "じょうず", "front": "good at", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "へた", "front": "bad at", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "りょうり", "front": "cooking, cuisine", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "のみもの", "front": "drinks", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "たべもの", "front": "foods", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おんがく", "front": "music", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "うた", "front": "song", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "え", "front": "picture", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "もしもし", "front": "hello(using on phone)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "どうして", "front": "why, what is the reason", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "どう", "front": "how", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ぜんぜん", "front": "not at all", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "すこし", "front": "little bit", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "たくさん", "front": "many, a lot", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "だいたい", "front": "almost, general, substantially, about much", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "こども", "front": "children", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おくさん", "front": "your wife, his wife, wife", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "つま/かない", "front": "(my) wife", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "しゅじん", "front": "(my) husband", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ごしゅじん", "front": "(your) husband", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "やくそく", "front": "promise, agreement", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ようじ", "front": "tasks, things to do", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "よく", "front": "often, well", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "どんな", "front": "which one", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "から", "front": "because, from", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "はやく", "front": "fast, early, quickly", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "きれい", "front": "beautiful, clean", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "しずか", "front": "quiet", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "にぎやか", "front": "lively", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ゆうめい", "front": "famous", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "しんせつ", "front": "kind", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "げんき", "front": "healthy, sound, cheerful", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ひま", "front": "free (time)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "べんり", "front": "convenient", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "すてき", "front": "fine, nice, wonderful", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おおきい", "front": "big, large", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ちいさい", "front": "small, little", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "あたらしい", "front": "new", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "あります", "front": "have", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "やきゅう", "front": "baseball", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "りょこう", "front": "trip", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "じ", "front": "character(language)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "じかん", "front": "time,  hour", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ふるい", "front": "old (not of age)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "いい (よい)", "front": "good", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "わるい", "front": "bad", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "あつい", "front": "hot", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "さむい", "front": "cold (temperature)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "つめたい", "front": "cold (to the touch)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "むずかしい", "front": "difficult", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "やさしい", "front": "easy", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "たかい", "front": "expensive, tall, high", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "やすい", "front": "inexpensive", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ひくい", "front": "low", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おもしろい", "front": "interesting", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "おいしい", "front": "delicious, tasty", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "いそがしい", "front": "busy", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "たのしい", "front": "enjoyable", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "しろい", "front": "white", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "くろい", "front": "black", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "あかい", "front": "red", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "あおい", "front": "blue", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "さくら", "front": "cherry blossom", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "やま", "front": "mountain", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "まち", "front": "town, city", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "くるま", "front": "car, vehicle", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "ところ", "front": "place", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "りょう", "front": "dormitory", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "べんきょう", "front": "study", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "せいかつ", "front": "life", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "しごと", "front": "work, business", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "どう", "front": "how", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "どんな", "front": "what kind of", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "どれ", "front": "which one (of three or more)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "とても", "front": "very", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "あまり", "front": "not so (used with negatives)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "そして", "front": "and (used to connect sentences)", "status": "notRemember" },
      { "back": "が", "front": "~, but ~", "status": "notRemember" }
    ]
}
